<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Suryansh Jaiswal</title>
    <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Suryansh Jaiswal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Product Management: Unique Challenges in the UAE Compared to the World</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world&#34;&gt;Decoding Product Management: Unique Challenges in the UAE Compared to the World&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Product management has become a pivotal role in businesses worldwide, adapting products to meet ever-evolving market needs and customer expectations. However, in the UAE, product managers face distinct challenges not as prevalent in other parts of the world. This post explores these unique hurdles and offers insights into navigating them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-diversity-and-consumer-behavior&#34;&gt;Cultural Diversity and Consumer Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UAE&amp;rsquo;s population is a rich tapestry of ethnicities, with expatriates making up a substantial portion of the residents. This diversity significantly influences product management strategies in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Aspiring Product Manager&#39;s Guide to Mastering User-Centric Design in 2024</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-aspiring-product-manager-s-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-aspiring-product-manager-s-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-aspiring-product-managers-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024&#34;&gt;The Aspiring Product Manager&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Mastering User-Centric Design in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving tech landscape of 2024, mastering user-centric design is more crucial than ever for aspiring product managers. This guide provides a comprehensive approach to understanding and implementing user-centric design principles to create products that truly resonate with users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-user-centric-design&#34;&gt;Understanding User-Centric Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;User-centric design (UCD) is a framework that places the user at the heart of the design and development process. This approach aims to tailor products to meet the specific needs and wants of users, enhancing user satisfaction and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Insider’s Guide to Breaking into Product Management in Dubai’s Thriving Tech Scene</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-insider-s-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubai-s-thriving-tech-scene-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-insider-s-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubai-s-thriving-tech-scene-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-insiders-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubais-thriving-tech-scene&#34;&gt;The Insider’s Guide to Breaking into Product Management in Dubai’s Thriving Tech Scene&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dubai’s tech scene is booming, with startups and multinational companies alike seeking innovative minds to lead their products to success. Product management is a critical role in this ecosystem, acting as a bridge between engineering, design, and market strategy. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to break into product management in Dubai, here’s how you can make your mark.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-role-and-responsibilities-of-a-product-manager&#34;&gt;Understanding the Role and Responsibilities of a Product Manager&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Product managers (PMs) are often considered the “CEOs of the product.” They oversee the development, implementation, and success of a product from conception to launch and beyond. Key responsibilities include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
