<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Suryansh Jaiswal</title>
    <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Suryansh Jaiswal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Data Centers in Scaling AI Products: Strategies for Product Managers</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-role-of-data-centers-in-scaling-ai-products-strategies-for-product-managers-2025-06-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-role-of-data-centers-in-scaling-ai-products-strategies-for-product-managers-2025-06-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-role-of-data-centers-in-scaling-ai-products-strategies-for-product-managers&#34;&gt;The Role of Data Centers in Scaling AI Products: Strategies for Product Managers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-data-center-impact-on-ai-product-performance&#34;&gt;Understanding Data Center Impact on AI Product Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data centers are critical for AI operations due to their role in computing power and data storage. Effective utilization of data centers impacts latency, compliance, and cost-efficiency:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency&lt;/strong&gt;: AI applications, particularly those requiring real-time insights, depend on low latency. Data center proximity to end-users reduces transmission delay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance&lt;/strong&gt;: Geographical location of data centers can affect regulatory compliance, especially with laws around data sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Froodo: My Entrepreneurial Journey to 500 Daily Orders</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/building-froodo-journey-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/building-froodo-journey-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-froodo-my-entrepreneurial-journey-to-500-daily-orders&#34;&gt;Building Froodo: My Entrepreneurial Journey to 500 Daily Orders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Embarking on an entrepreneurial journey feels like assembling a parachute mid-fall. Here&amp;rsquo;s my story from 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I co-founded &lt;strong&gt;Froodo&lt;/strong&gt;, a subscription-based healthy snacking business delivering fresh, chilled cut fruit boxes to customers&amp;rsquo; doorsteps. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a business — it was a crash course in customer acquisition, growth hacking, hiring, finance, operations, and customer service.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-aha-moment-identifying-the-problem&#34;&gt;The AHA Moment: Identifying the Problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea came from a personal pain point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Boosted SWVL’s GMV with Cross-Selling Packages</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/swvl-cross-sell-gmv-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/swvl-cross-sell-gmv-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-boosted-swvls-gmv-with-cross-selling-packages&#34;&gt;How I Boosted SWVL’s GMV with Cross-Selling Packages&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I joined &lt;strong&gt;SWVL&lt;/strong&gt; in February 2021, just after the pandemic, to lead growth products. One of the most promising levers was the &lt;strong&gt;Packages&lt;/strong&gt; product—a prepaid ride bundle that allowed users to buy multiple rides at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For users: it meant lower per-ride costs.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For SWVL: it drove higher &lt;strong&gt;LTV&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;retention&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;ride frequency&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The mission was clear: increase package sales to directly impact &lt;strong&gt;GMV&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Built and Launched a SaaS Platform for Creators and Got 5000 Signups in the First Month with Limited Budget</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/shooty-saas-launch-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/shooty-saas-launch-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-built-and-launched-a-saas-platform-for-creators-and-got-5000-signups-in-the-first-month-with-limited-budget&#34;&gt;How I Built and Launched a SaaS Platform for Creators and Got 5000 Signups in the First Month with Limited Budget&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-from-scratch&#34;&gt;Starting from Scratch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I left SWVL, I joined &lt;strong&gt;Shooty&lt;/strong&gt;, an early-stage startup with no product vision and a small tech team. The shift—from a structured product environment to a blank slate—forced me to build everything from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first challenge: what are we building?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The second: who do we need to build it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Increased Nykaa&#39;s Mega Sales Revenue by 10% Using a Simple CRO Hack and Data</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/nykaa-mega-sale-cro-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/nykaa-mega-sale-cro-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-increased-nykaas-mega-sales-revenue-by-10-using-a-simple-cro-hack-and-data&#34;&gt;How I Increased Nykaa&amp;rsquo;s Mega Sales Revenue by 10% Using a Simple CRO Hack and Data&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;company-background&#34;&gt;Company Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nykaa is India’s leading e-retailer for beauty and cosmetics—comparable to Sephora in the U.S.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Listed on the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE), Nykaa held a valuation of &lt;strong&gt;$6B&lt;/strong&gt; at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-context&#34;&gt;Project Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2016, I was heading Product and Analytics at Nykaa. One of my key mandates was improving &lt;strong&gt;conversion rates&lt;/strong&gt; during &lt;strong&gt;Mega Sales&lt;/strong&gt;, which were high-stakes, high-volume events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Used My Product Management Learnings to Help a Friend’s Offline Business</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/how-i-used-my-product-management-learnings-to-help-a-friends-offline-business-2025-06-13how-i-used-my-product-management-learnings-in-offline-business-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/how-i-used-my-product-management-learnings-to-help-a-friends-offline-business-2025-06-13how-i-used-my-product-management-learnings-in-offline-business-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-used-my-product-management-learnings-to-help-a-friends-offline-business&#34;&gt;How I Used My Product Management Learnings to Help a Friend’s Offline Business&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It all started when I was having a conversation with my childhood friend who owns a baby product shop in a small town in India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He asked me, “We have been friends for so long but I still do not know what you do for work.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I told him about Product Management and tried to explain it with the usual jargon—but obviously, he got confused. Then I simplified: we identify problems that customers face and solve them in a way that&amp;rsquo;s good for both the customer and the business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the AI Revolution: How Product Managers Can Stay Relevant and Thrive</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/navigating-the-ai-revolution-how-product-managers-can-stay-relevant-and-thrive-2025-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/navigating-the-ai-revolution-how-product-managers-can-stay-relevant-and-thrive-2025-06-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-the-ai-revolution-how-product-managers-can-stay-relevant-and-thrive&#34;&gt;Navigating the AI Revolution: How Product Managers Can Stay Relevant and Thrive&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapid advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) are transforming industries across the globe. For product managers, the AI revolution presents both unprecedented opportunities and formidable challenges. Understanding how to navigate these changes effectively is crucial for staying relevant and thriving in your career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;embracing-change-and-understanding-ai&#34;&gt;Embracing Change and Understanding AI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI technologies are reshaping how products are developed, marketed, and managed. As a product manager, gaining a foundational understanding of AI and its implications is critical. Start by exploring the basics of AI, including machine learning, natural language processing, and robotic process automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Product Management: Unique Challenges in the UAE Compared to the World</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;decoding-product-management-unique-challenges-in-the-uae-compared-to-the-world&#34;&gt;Decoding Product Management: Unique Challenges in the UAE Compared to the World&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Product management has become a pivotal role in businesses worldwide, adapting products to meet ever-evolving market needs and customer expectations. However, in the UAE, product managers face distinct challenges not as prevalent in other parts of the world. This post explores these unique hurdles and offers insights into navigating them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-diversity-and-consumer-behavior&#34;&gt;Cultural Diversity and Consumer Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UAE&amp;rsquo;s population is a rich tapestry of ethnicities, with expatriates making up a substantial portion of the residents. This diversity significantly influences product management strategies in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the PRD in AI Applications: A Comprehensive Guide for Product Managers</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-art-of-the-prd-in-ai-applications-a-comprehensive-guide-for-product-managers-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-art-of-the-prd-in-ai-applications-a-comprehensive-guide-for-product-managers-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-art-of-the-prd-in-ai-applications-a-comprehensive-guide-for-product-managers&#34;&gt;The Art of the PRD in AI Applications: A Comprehensive Guide for Product Managers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving field of artificial intelligence, the importance of a well-crafted Product Requirements Document (PRD) cannot be overstated. As a bridge between the visionary and the practical, a PRD translates high-level business and user needs into detailed, actionable requirements that guide the development team. This guide will walk you through the essential elements of creating effective PRDs specifically tailored for AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Aspiring Product Manager&#39;s Guide to Mastering User-Centric Design in 2024</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-aspiring-product-manager-s-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-aspiring-product-manager-s-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-aspiring-product-managers-guide-to-mastering-user-centric-design-in-2024&#34;&gt;The Aspiring Product Manager&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Mastering User-Centric Design in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving tech landscape of 2024, mastering user-centric design is more crucial than ever for aspiring product managers. This guide provides a comprehensive approach to understanding and implementing user-centric design principles to create products that truly resonate with users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-user-centric-design&#34;&gt;Understanding User-Centric Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;User-centric design (UCD) is a framework that places the user at the heart of the design and development process. This approach aims to tailor products to meet the specific needs and wants of users, enhancing user satisfaction and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Insider’s Guide to Breaking into Product Management in Dubai’s Thriving Tech Scene</title>
      <link>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-insider-s-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubai-s-thriving-tech-scene-2025-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://suryanshjaiswal.com/posts/the-insider-s-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubai-s-thriving-tech-scene-2025-06-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-insiders-guide-to-breaking-into-product-management-in-dubais-thriving-tech-scene&#34;&gt;The Insider’s Guide to Breaking into Product Management in Dubai’s Thriving Tech Scene&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dubai is rapidly becoming a hub for technology and innovation in the Middle East, rivalling traditional tech-heavy regions. With this growth comes an increased demand for product managers who can navigate the complexities of the tech market and steer products to success. If you’re looking to break into product management in this vibrant scene, here are some insider tips and strategies to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
